- Dad, can I come too?
- Oh-hhh.
Not till you're older.
But then you can sit at the
head of the table, by me.
Go to your nanny.
I'm very proud of musab.
I don't want him to grow up
to be a slave...
a slave like me,
like all of us.
We don't want our children
to be slaves.
No.
Wait.
Okay, time for homework.
Can I go and visit
my mother first?
Sure.
Musab.
Musab!
Hide and seek!
One, two...
They call us warlords.
Lords of what?
We are landowners,
leaders of provinces.
But what does that count for, if
the government takes its orders
from Soviets or America?
We are pawns, and they push us
where they choose to.
Well, I won't be pushed
any further.
14, 15.
Musab, let's go back
into the house.
We can play inside, okay?
Musab!
Somebody help me!
Where is my son?
Musab!
Saeed! Saeed!
We have to stop the fire.
Musab!
Musab.
Musab. Please.
Oh, please!
Who told them we were here?
Who is the traitor?
Habibi. Habibi.
Why are you here?
Why have you come with that
camera around your neck?
I... I was just
traveling.
In a war zone?
There was no fighting
when I got here.
But there is now.
No, I...
I ran out of money.
Khalid's offered me a job.
In his bed.
That's how you fooled him.
Spy!
Murderer!
Who told the Soviets?
- - Shit.
Who's running away?
Who?
Blood will have blood.
- And then you've got a month
- To work on your final papers.
Okay? All right,
have a good weekend.
So do you know who you're
going to work with?
I'm working with Tanya.
Right. Okay, cool.
- It's mina, right?
- Yeah.
- Are you American?
- Yeah. Well,
my parents aren't,
but I was born there,
so I guess the accent stuck.
Bad luck.
Mina.
Frederick.
I think these are your
coursework suggestions.
You dumped them
in my pidge by mistake.
Thank you.
So, um...
Mom, I want to live at college.
We're only eight Miles away.
I'm not asking you to pay for it.
I'll get my own job.
Mi, I don't know if we can
keep this going without you.
What about after Oxford?
I can't keep working
at the farm forever.
What do you want?
My own life.
I don't know.
Mina, what's a blow job?
What?
What are you reading?
Okay, that's bedtime.
Oh, but I want to stay up.
Did you read "j-17"
when you were 17?
No, I read it when
I was nine, like you.
Are you going to live
somewhere else?
What?
Who told you that?
I heard dad tell mom
you was getting a job
at the supermarket
so you could leave
and live somewhere else.
Dee,
do you really want to stay up?
You have to be quiet though.
Shh shh shh.
Shh.
Okay, come on.
Come on.
Up we go. Okay.
Why is mom screaming?
Shh.
Shh. Shh. Don't let
them see you, okay?
There are robbers in the house.
Come with me.
Get in.
Get out of here!
Leave her alone!
Tie them.
Let go of me!
- Don't touch her.
What have you got
for me here, right?
Now get mina and the girl.
How do they know your name?
Careful.
Don't injure them,
- not until we are filming.
- No!
Don't fucking move.
Mommy, mommy.
Come here.
- Get the phone.
- It's dead.
- Run!
-  Mom.
Now!
I swear to God,
hurt them and I will fuck you.
I swear to God
I'll fucking kill them!
You would have killed them already!
Now, mina, now!
Run, go go!
Go!
Go. Come on,
let's go. Run.
- Take her.
- Mom.
Ring this number.
Just say the code.
- The phone's dead.
-  What?
Right, out of the window.
To the neighbors, go.
- No, mom.
-  I shall stay here with mom.
Now don't worry. She'll be all right.
It's just a surface wound.
I'll be fine.
Go, please, for me.
- - Jesus.
- Go.
-  Get Dee out of here now.
- Go go go go go go go.
- Mom. Mom.
Get Dee out of here!
Go!
Please please.
The village shop... there's...
there's a payphone.
Oh my God, they're following us.
Dee, run!
Shh.
Shit.
- Help.
- Closed.
Please, there's someone after us. Please,
you have to let me use your phone.
- Who?
- I don't know.
Don't you recognize us
from the farm?
Help. Someone's trying
to kill us.
Go around the back.
Around the back.
- Please, you have to help us.
- Come on, come in quickly.
Someone's trying to kill us and
they already have our parents.
Tell me later.
I'll go and get the van.
Hello. Hello.
Is that the police?
Yeah, I've got two girls
here that...
how are you feeling?
-  Where's my sister?
- Dee's fine.
Actually she's... she's
just a little bruised.
Wh... what...
what happened to my parents?
I'm sorry.
Look, I'm sorry, I'm going to
have to ask you a few questions.
My name's Olivia.
I'm here to help you.
We received your phone call.
Now can you describe
your attackers?
You haven't caught them?
No.
They were dark-skinned.
How many?
Three.
And one of them had
a tattoo on his hand.
Can you draw it?
Here.
Excuse me, I need
to take this to fax.
You're not gonna
tell me who did it?
They knew my name!
Wait!
I'm not answering
any more of your questions
until you tell me who did this.
Does the name Khalid zeerak
mean anything to you?
Were you aware that your mother
traveled before you were born?
She told me Turkey
and... and Yemen.
And the wakhan corridor? Where
it was used as a silk route
from Tajikistan all the way
through to China?
Well, she... your mother took
some of these pictures.
She lived there
for almost a year.
She never told me that.
And while she was hiking,
she ran into some bandits
who took everything
and left her stranded.
And it was then that she came
to the house of this Khalid.
He employed your mother
as a nanny to his son.
Why are you telling me this?
Because Khalid is a warlord.
Do you understand?
He's a terrorist.
And...
Less than a year after your
mother went to work for him,
someone told the Soviets
where he lived
and they bombed his house.
Your mother escaped
and the Americans asked us
to find her a new identity,
because they knew that
he would hunt her down
and kill her no matter what.
His son was killed in the bomb.
Are you saying
that my mother was a spy?
No.
She was in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
But Khalid thought she was.
Your dad knew too.
He was ex-army.
Why now?
Something must have
tipped him off
that your mother
was still alive,
perhaps when you moved over
from the states or...
do you use any
social networking sites,
like Facebook or Flickr or...?
Are you trying to say
that this is my fault?
No. God no.
No no no.
I'm sorry, I...
I just...
I just want to go see
my parents, okay?
Would you like to come through?
Mina, this is Simon.
He works for me.
I want to see my sister now.
You can't.
You'll be twice as easy
to spot together.
Why does Khalid want us anyway?
We didn't even do anything.
His son died.
It's a vendetta culture there.
I mean, people get killed for
things their grandparents did.
They tried to kill
your sister too.
You saw it yourself.
If you know who he is,
why can't you catch him?
We've been looking for,
what, 10 months?
That whole region is
a diplomatic no-go zone.
Officially we're not
even there.
That's why I've hired
Simon unofficially.
He's not British
intelligence. He's a...
an independent contractor.
Just let me talk to her.
She's nine years old. We can't
trust her not to tell...
what?
That you're still alive.
She thinks I'm dead?
Mina, everyone does.
Who's sue Walker?
You are.
Nice place.
The...
The owners are away for six
months then we'll move you on.
You'll be used
to sue Walker by then.
Who's sue Walker?
It's your name.
Simon, please take me
to my sister.
No one needs to know.
I'm not paid to make
decisions like that, mina.
I'm sorry.
Come on, I want
to show you something.
It's a penthouse, so you...
you can have a roof garden.
Thought it might make you
feel more at home.
Sorry about the...
the view.
I'll be in england
till the end of the week.
My number's in there.
Dee?
Sorry, this number
is no longer available.
I'll be fine.
Go, please, for me.
Go.
Mom!
Dee!
There's a new study out from the London
school of hygiene and tropical medicine...
which sounds like
a fun school to go to.
They did a study on obesity
and calculated
-  34 billion lbs overweight.
Soon we'll need a rascal scooter
to help us get round the side.
You see, the average
human body weight is 137 lbs
and in north America
it's 189 lbs.
Another terrorist attack in
the wakhan corridor last night.
Fanatical anti-Western
nationalist Khalid zeerak
claimed responsibility
as part of his ongoing campaign
to prevent oil company nasco
drilling in the region.
The chief adviser to nasco,
Mohammed ibrahami,
was targeted and killed
in the attack.
His son dagar will continue
his father's work.
Let this be a message
to foreign imperialists
and the traitors who help them:
This is just the beginning.
- - Mina, it's me... Simon.
Mina.
Mina, I can't go
until I've seen you.
All right.
Well...
I don't know that I should
even show you this,
but I want you to know
that she's okay.
You need to let me talk to her.
I can't do that.
You know I can't do that.
- 'Cause you're not paid to do that.
- No, I'm not paid to do this.
I am sticking my neck out as
it is, showing you that video.
Great, thank you so much.
Now I'm gonna
tell you something.
I don't know how long it's
gonna take to find Khalid,
but I do know this...
that you have to lead
the life that you have now.
You have to live it.
I'm sticking
around here tonight.
I can help you tidy up
your apartment.
I don't want you to help
me tidy up my apartment.
You need to put one foot
in front of the other and...
I can't do that
right now, okay?
You have to live, now.
- I'm helping you.
- Take this.
- I am helping you.
- You're not helping me.
Stop talking to me like
I'm a fucking kid, okay?
Stop acting like
a fucking kid, okay?
You know what?
Get out!
Just leave.
She doesn't seem to be here.
Okay.
Please leave a message
after the tone.
- I'll be back
- In one minute.
Shit.
Hey.
Bitch, come here.
I didn't show you this one.
Mina, we know that Khalid
raped your mother.
She said it was a
one-night stand in Yemen.
She was trying to protect you.
Look, we... we didn't want
to have to tell...
we didn't expect this to...
you're his only heir
and he wants you back.
I think I'm gonna be sick.
He's a psychopath,
and something about you
just makes him crazier.
But it was really unlike
him to take these risks.
Sorry, do you want
to use my bathroom?
What are you suggesting?
- Probably we've got a mole
- In this department.
They found her sister
tonight too.
Jesus. Is she okay?
- Yes, she's fine,
- But this time
they weren't shooting
tranquillizers.
I mean, imagine,
if he did find her,
she'd lead us straight to him.
How's my sister?
She's fine.
She...
we're just gonna keep
moving from place to place
until you catch him, right?
Or until he catches us?
No, look, we will...
we will catch him.
When?
It could take years.
- Let him catch me.
- What?
You can't tell me you haven't
thought about it before, right?
It's really easy.
You just track me,
and then I lead you
right to him.
No, look, we...
we don't do things like
that with civilians.
And if anyone found out, this
whole department would be shut...
then don't let anyone find out.
Let Simon do it.
He's not officially
working for you, right?
And I'm legally dead anyway.
There you are.
Sorry about that.
Had to make it look real.
Do you think Khalid will really
believe that you kidnapped me?
I don't think he'd
trace it back to me.
And even if he could...
Somewhere you can breathe.
So I've got a few
that I just want you
to just take a look at,
so that it's not too crazy
when you're out there.
This is an m16.
This is mostly what our
guys are gonna be with.
Just so you've got
a sense of it.
Don't point that at me.
Don't ever point a gun at someone
when you're not gonna use it.
Here, I'll show you
how to do the clip.
That's there,
and there's a bit more
that goes in there.
Pops back in.
That's the safety catch.
And then just line it up.
You want to pull this...
brace this into your...
here, brace this into
your shoulder like that.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
And then just
line up the sight.
- You got it?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Um...
We'll move onto those...
that ak-47 first.
But I'll just show you
a couple of pistols.
That's the glock.
If you want to weigh that up?
You ready?
Want to try it?
Put your hands up.
Now.
That's good.
That's really good.
So choose your weapon.
Come on, mina, think.
This pencil...
here, grab it,
jab it here,
under the ear... deadly.
This mirror...
grab a towel,
smash it.
Will they kill him?
Well... no no.
Olivia wants him
taken alive for information.
But after that
he'll be executed, right?
Well, he'll stand trial.
Simon, he killed my parents.
I know.
But there's knowing it,
and then
there is proving it.
Oh, that's Olivia.
Working very late, as ever.
Does she have any family?
Her department's
her family... literally.
Her dad is probably the
best operative they have.
Is that why she got the job?
No no no.
He's strictly by the book.
That is why she didn't
want to send you in...
in case dad found out.
Well, he'll be happy
when she finds Khalid.
No shit.
What about you? What are you
gonna do with the ransom?
I don't know.
I've had my eye
on this Bentley.
I meant, are you going to hand
it over to the government?
Mina, I work for money.
Well yeah, but for the
good guys too, right?
Yeah, of course I prefer that.
But it's just not always
that simple, you know.
Sometimes it's like now...
they send me in
because of some
diplomatic issue.
Sometimes they just don't want
to get their hands dirty.
So have you done things that
you thought were wrong?
So whose initials are those?
Oh, these are my wife's.
She's gone.
It's a long time ago.
What happened?
That is a long story.
You know, in school they said
that smoking takes
five years off your life.
Oh yeah?
At mine they said 10.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't...
I thought you were...
- Yeah.
- ...Still...
We're on.
-  You up for this?
- Yeah.
Okay.
It used to be that you could
just swallow a homing device
or stick it up your ass.
But I think Khalid's men
are too shrewd for that.
I don't think they'll
have seen one of these.
Will it hurt?
A little bit.
Argh!
Fucking...
wow, you're tough.
I've seen 18-stone marines
faint from that.
Now...
Let's see if we've got you.
There you are.
Now that's gonna bruise
quite badly,
so camouflage.
Take your pick.
Simon.
Yeah?
I was just wondering if you...
if you ever felt...
holy shit!
- Take his wallet. Take his wallet.
- Simon.
- American? English?
- Simon, wake up!
No.
Please.
Hey?
Rich?
Pay good ransom?
Is he your dad?
What?
My dad's Khalid zeerak.
Sit on your hands.
Sit on your hands!
Sit on...!
So...
We are in big trouble, huh?
Lie to me again, bitch,
and I'll kill you, okay?
We're still in the air.
I can't get someone to you
for two hours. Over.
Jesus, okay.
Out.
No one will pay for me.
Well, we're gonna use you then.
No.
No! No!
Whoa whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
Stop. Stop.
Simon.
Come in, Simon.
Olivia, did you copy?
Yes.
Do the bandits still have her?
Three hostiles down.
No sign of mina.
She's still on the move.
Whoa whoa whoa.
Whoa whoa whoa whoa whoa.
Alf dollar.
-  Alf? Alf?
- Dollar.
Yeah?
- Huh?
- Jacket.
You want this?
Sorry about that, mate.
-  Salaam.
-  Salaam alaikum.
Yallah yallah.
- Move.
Allahu akbar...
Stay.
Did they hurt you?
- You're safe here with me.
- Who are you?
Saba abdali.
I work with your father Khalid.
That was not supposed
to happen to you.
Those boys that took you...
I'm afraid my country's
full of those opportunists.
You work for a terrorist.
First I need to run
some tests on you.
Now I could force you
and I'll call abu back.
Or if you let me do it...
easier.
Your choice.
It's supposed to mean freedom
from oppression and rules.
Okay.
Get dressed now.
The results are positive.
I've got to go out now.
I've written
my cell number on top,
in case you might need me.
Understand your father's
need to see you.
He's lost his only son.
Try to respect that.
He's upstairs.
You...
Look like...
like me.
How dare you?
You think you can kill my mother
and I'll still be your daughter?
What?
Your mother?
- Wait.
- What is that?
Let her go. Let her go.
Let her go!
I don't understand.
Your mother is dead?
Your men killed her.
Wait. Stop.
I thought she was dead,
20 years.
Look.
Last week I find out
she's alive.
And we have a daughter.
She called you mina...
my language, pashto,
for "love."
Now you say she's dead.
She was murdered
three weeks ago.
Who?
Tell me who
and I will kill them.
Olivia, is that
our guys coming in?
Who's this?
I thought you were a terrorist.
Me?
You should see what dagar would do
without me to protect our people.
I think something's gone
horribly wrong.
But you can explain it
to them, right?
Them?
British intelligence.
I led them to you.
Olivia, are these our guys?
What the fuck is going on?
Fuck.
Olivia, what the fuck?
Olivia, dagar must have
hacked our signals.
-
- Whoa whoa whoa.
All right.
Whoa.
All right, all right.
I don't understand.
Go. Make sure
no one is left alive.
In English, please,
for our guest.
I knew she'd make you come
crawling from under your rock.
Your love is your weakness.
Before you die,
you'll watch me kill her,
like you killed my father.
I didn't know your father
was in that factory.
Don't tell me you're sorry.
He was helping you sell
our people to foreigners.
I'm just sorry you weren't
in there with him.
-  Get down!
Help me!
Say it.
Khalid...
No!
No no.
No, please. No!
Say goodbye to your daughter.
Leave her.
- Leave her!
- Say it.
-  No!
Mina!
Oh oh.
Ahmed!
Just... just... just...
you're not a killer.
Come on.
Mina, come on.
We have to go.
Ahmed!
Ahmed.
In here.
Out out out.
Up up up.
Sir.
You're making a big
fucking mistake.
That girl is
under u.K. Protection.
What? I thought
she was legally dead.
Get down. Now!
Get down.
- Shoot them off the road.
- What?
Shoot them off the road, now.
It's not working.
I led them to you.
Get out of the car.
We can hide
between those rocks.
Get out!
Save yourself...
For me.
No!
No no no no no!
She's dead.
Shall we kill him?
He won't be causing us
any more trouble.
He's just a paid idiot.
Go. Get out of here.
A victory in the battle
against terrorism today,
as terrorist Khalid zeerak
was killed
in an attack
in the capital city of bogh,
where he was believed
to have been living
for almost a year
without detection.
It's unclear how intelligence
obtained information
as to his whereabouts.
The raid, conducted by a
specialist local armed force,
occurred in the early hours
of this morning.
It brought about an end to
Khalid's reign of terror
- over the tribe of dagar ibrahami.
- No.
Nasco oil is and will continue
to destroy this region.
My people's homes
are being cleared
to make way for the pipeline.
As long as I live,
I will stop at nothing
to expose and end this.
Saba.
Saba?
Oh, sorry.
Excuse me.
Simon?
Mina?
Is that you?
Oh my God.
You're alive.
How?
I saw you in Khalid's car.
You... he kidnapped you.
No.
No, he...
you were there?
Yeah, um...
I've found out
where Olivia's holed up.
You're not safe out here.
You follow me
at a distance.
Keep your head down, okay?
Okay.
You're alive.
And the man who killed
your parents is dead.
No.
It was dagar. He made
us think it was Khalid.
- What?
There's still trouble.
Now I told you I wanted it
to be cleared by tonight.
It will be.
There are only a few
villages left to clear.
My men are on their way
up there now.
You knew once Khalid was dead,
there would be no resistance.
Look, there's to be no mention
of Khalid or village clearances
or your role in this
to harm helder, okay?
You're just the local
advisor, all right?
You know there'll be
no payout without me.
There are plenty more
of your type out there.
It's not your oil
to bargain with.
Careful, you're starting
to sound like Khalid.
Dagar, we both know
you're motivated by money.
Fine. See you
at the compound later.
Mina, I'm on your side.
No, you're not.
You work for dagar.
I didn't know that, I swear.
Intelligence don't either. Olivia
clearly has her own private agenda.
He murdered my parents.
Don't you get it? Olivia told
them where my family was
so that they could get to Khalid.
She... she let them die.
All right.
You're alive.
Your sister is alive.
I have a place in Canada
for when I retire.
- You'll be safe there.
- What about these people?
Dagar's destroying their homes
so that the oil company
can drill.
He's taking everything
from them.
And he's going to get away with
it, because we gave him Khalid.
Didn't you ask where your
money was coming from?
I'm not a politician.
So you're not gonna
do anything.
I'll tell you
I'm going to go to Olivia.
I'm gonna ask for my money.
Otherwise she thinks
I'm a threat.
And I'm gonna get
a plane from her
and I'm going to get you
out of here alive.
And then we'll testify?
You think they're gonna believe you...
Khalid's daughter?
There won't be a shred of evidence
linking Olivia to any of this.
But they'll trust you.
Listen, this is the real world,
and people get fucked over.
I'm gonna tell you
you can stand up for a
principle and you can die,
or you can walk away
and you can live.
I want you to live.
Don't fucking touch me.
I'll have that plane
tomorrow night...
when you can see some sense!
It was getting infected.
You could have died.
We can't let them
get away with this.
What can we do?
Khalid gave us hope
and leadership.
They're inspecting
the oil compound tonight.
- We need to film it.
You want them to stand trial?
No, I want proof.
And then I want to kill them.
Oh, you won't be able
to use that.
It's too dangerous, too noisy.
You just want to get in
and get out.
But you can use this.
Do you think you have it in you
to slit a man's throat?
I am a warlord's
daughter, aren't I?
How can you get us in?
My cousin can.
He drives the employees'
luggage in every week
from the airport
to the oil company.
It's an empty bus. He can
meet us there, on the way.
It's about 15 Miles from
here, at a checkpoint.
Will it be safe for you?
No.
- The checkpoint.
- Get down and stay down.
I'll sort this.
He'll be here in 15 minutes.
Mr. helder, Mr. ibrahami,
I see you've both met.
All the last-minute glitches
have been ironed out
so we are ready to proceed.
- Because, if there's
- Any sign of trouble,
we don't want another
Niger delta on our hands.
I assure you the resistance
died with Khalid.
I'm sure it's nothing.
Simon.
I was worried about you.
Cut the crap, Olivia.
What?
You gave me no fucking idea
what I was walking into.
And you didn't expect me
to walk out again, did you?
It's all right.
I just want my money.
Of course you do.
You leave the talking to me.
Please don't worry.
He's a professional.
He's discreet.
If he wasn't,
he'd be dead by now.
- You didn't tell me
- There'd be a third share.
I'll pay him out of my share.
Abdul.
Alarm! Alarm! Alarm!
- - What the fuck is that?
I'm sure it's nothing.
You fucking bitch.
You're the reason
my parents are dead.
No, okay? I told him
not to hurt anyone.
He was just meant to kidnap
you, so we could get to Khalid.
And rape this country.
This country was fucked
before you were born.
People get killed here
every day.
Terrorists are trained here.
The oil company
would stop all that.
It's better for everyone.
You're believing
your own bullshit.
Because if there's
any sign of trouble,
we don't want another
Niger delta on our hands.
I assure you the resistance
died with...
you'll never prove
I was ever here.
Did you send
that clip to anyone?
You're not just hurting me.
You are compromising
the whole of British
intelligence.
Scared your dad will see it?
Look, you stupid little bitch,
you are not gonna
fuck this up for me.
You're legally dead already.
Who did you send that clip to?
- Miss hawks...
Nothing.
It's a false alarm.
Don't let her
out of your sight.
A dog hit the fence.
Sometimes I think
our security's too good.
Right, business.
Before I go, I'd like
to see the pump working.
Of course.
As you can see,
Mr. helder,
this is the main housing
for the pump station.
Yallah yallah, mushi mushi.
- So I hope
- You're satisfied.
It'll be at full capacity
within a week.
Sir, there is
no smoking in here.
Help! Help!
Help! Let me out!
- Oh good...
- Simon.
Go get Olivia.
Go!
You don't have permission
to takeoff.
- Stay calm. Calm down.
- Stop the fucking plane!
- Look...
- Get up!
You can go see your sister now.
Will you be okay?
Yeah, I'm a hard ass.
You know that.
I'll be out
in a couple of days.
That's not what I mean.
It's over.
Go get your life back.
- Hello. Mina,
- Is that you?
Yeah.
- You're gonna
- Love it here.